Gorakh Shetty

♥Sydney, Australia | ♥gorock397@gmail.com | □0404781370 | In LinkedIn | ▲ GitHub | ♥ Twitter

SUMMARY

A Tech enthusiast and Junior Software Developer with experience in front-end and back-end development. Has a strong portfolio demonstrating experience in building React apps and working with APIs. With an eagerness to learn and a passion for front-end technologies, confident in contributing to the success of the Phocas Analytics team. Focuses on effective and result-driven solutions to business needs utilizing theoretical knowledge, personal experience, and certifications.

EXPERIENCE

Cook

Rose Cafe

July 2020 - Present, Sydney, Australia

- Demonstrated ability to work in a fast-paced environment, prioritizing tasks and ensuring timely delivery of high-quality products, which translates to being able handle multiple projects and deadlines as a software developer.
- Collaborated with other kitchen staff to ensure smooth and efficient service, demonstrating the ability to work well within a team and communicate effectively, which is crucial for working collaboratively with other developers.
- Developed and executed menus in accordance with dietary needs and customer preferences, which translates to being able to understand and meet user requirements as a software developer.

Jr Front-End Web Developer

Creative Techno Solutions

January 2018 - July 2018, Dang, Nepal

- Worked closely with team leader and learned new web development tools and technologies.
- Designed website using HTML, CSS and Bootstrap.
- Worked with front-end team in building and maintaining e-learning content.

PROJECTS

DBS (Consulting Website)

Personal Project • February 2023 - Present

- Developed a consulting website for a client using a ReactJS framework.
- Designed and implemented a visually appealing, responsive and user-friendly website.
- · Utilized modern web development tools such as Webpack and Babel to bundle and convert code more effectively.
- Hosted the website on Netlify with GitHub integration, and configured continuous deployment for automatic updates to live website.
- Created reusable react components and followed best practices to ensure maintainability and scalability of the codebase.
- Worked independently to troubleshoot and resolve any hosting or deployment issues.

AI Image Generator

Personal Project • December 2022 - Present

- Developed an AI image generator using Vanilla JavaScript and the Open AI API.
- Utilized the Open AI API to generate custom images based on user input.
- Configured API requests to retrieve generated images based on user input.
- Utilized personal initiative to understand the capabilities and limitations of the Open AI API, and incorporated this knowledge into the project design.

RekognizeMe (Object Identification App)

Personal Project • July 2021 - October 2021

- Designed and developed and Android app in Java with Google Machine Learning (ML) Kit.
- · Utilized Firebase ML Kit for image labeling to detect and extract information about the objects in an image.
- Implemented SerpApi to access Google search results of the object identified in the image.

EDUCATION

Bachelors in information technology (Specialized in Software Development)

Charles Sturt University • Sydney, Australia • 2021

CERTIFICATIONS

Web Developer Bootcamp

Udemy • 2022

64 total hours Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

SKILLS

HTML5 & CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, ReactJS, DOM, Redux, Styled-Components, JSX, Express, NodeJS, MongoDB, APIs, Java, Git, Visual Studio Code, Android Studio